I think it's time for you to come in.
welcome (in shops, etc.)
Welcome to Snack Kyoko.
Finally.
I'm here.
It'll be like opening a snack bar before you know it.
I'm gonna have to wear that mask.
Just so you know, this is how it's done.
Acrylic sheets are used for splash protection.
There's a big one right here.
Yes, if you don't mind.
Could you take off that mask for me?
I'd like to talk to you.
What would you like to drink?
Highball, please!
You're welcome, Mom.
Thank you very much.
My mom also gave it to me.
Mom, I think we got it.
Can www.
Yes, it's the same thing, isn't it?
Yes, thank you.
Okay.
That's right.
That's very neat.
Sounds good.
It's cool.
This is also to match the colors of that Code for Japan.
Red dress.
Oh, yes. Thank you.
Thank you for your concern.
I tried to match them a little.
I don't really talk about work.
It's all about the community.
Or a geo-media community.
I wonder how much is in the open source community and so on.
I think I've known him for about 10 years.
I don't know if I've ever talked to you before.
I think I know who knows, maybe.
But now, in terms of titles.
Mr. Seki, President of Code for Japan
And Georepublic.
I run a geomedia systems company.
I don't know if it's representative.
That's a great image to have.
From the beginning, because I already have.
For example, after school, or after you start working.
You've been doing that kind of thing for a long time?
I'm not really sure what to say.
I'm just a regular businessman.
I don't feel that way at all, though.
I'm not interested in social issues at all.
Oh, yeah.
I was already so unserious that I dropped out of college.
I think I'm going to write something about social issues for my thesis.
No, not at all.
I was in a band.
Oh, right, right, right.
At first, I had a strong image of that.
That's right.
Well, then why is it that, with your history...
Thank you very much.
And a couple of snacks.
I was wondering if Seki-san likes sweets today.
I've been drinking a little.
A little bit of sweet chocolate.
I just found it.
Oh, something about a snack Kyoko.
He said that the selection of those snacks was bad.
A lot the first time.
Um, today's one might be hard to eat there, too.
If you think about it.
You know, the kind that looks like raw chocolate?
Maybe I'll get cocoa on my teeth.
It's like he's talking with it on all the time.
Have them eat clean.
Yes, sir.
It might be a little big, but...
It's also a bit like a beer.
It's true. Beer.
That's right.
I don't know.
It has beer kneaded into it.
Heh.
I found something like that.
yes
certainly
Thank you very much.
Cheers again.
Welcome to Snack Kyoko.
It's not like we drink like this.
Oh, no, not at all.
Well, I don't have a chance.
I don't know if it's possible to have a drink with Seki-san.
At the launch of an event or something.
I've been in groups with other people.
Most of them weren't there.
Launching in the first place, not staying that long.
If you join, you're gone or something.
Or something like that.
I'm not much of a drinker.
Maybe after an event or something.
But they're together.
I've also come to Tokyo from Kansai.
I had to go home early again.
Maybe not so much.
So today is really a bit unusual.
I'm glad.
I know, right?
So I'd really like to do something like this.
In what way?
I mean, work.
That's exactly the kind of social issue we're dealing with now.
I don't know, until I get there.
Since I was in a band.
Well, I've already got a job.
I really have a dozen or so.
It would take too long to say it all.
You know, basically.
I've been an engineer all my life.
I like the band.
That time is the most important for the band to be able to
Occupations that allow you to go home early
I'm choosing to be an engineer.
It just so happens that it is.
coinciding with that boom in the Internet.
Something about internet media.
It's like a sports portal site.
It's called Sportsnavi, or something like that.
There were ringtones in the music business back then.
I'll be streaming music on that mobile.
That kind of thing.
Or doing it.
And then there's the ad-serving company.
This company is called Sirius Technologies.
That's where a location-based ad delivery system like
I thought this was really interesting.
I didn't have a smart phone back then.
even if it's a traditional Japanese phone (e.g. cell phone)
The GPS is always installed.
All kinds of services are starting to appear.
This is some amazing internet.
I thought I'd make it more interesting.
So, you see...
I wanted to join a company that was involved in location-based information.
The first time I went in for that interview in a proper way.
That's the company.
And all the time before that.
I had a referral from someone I knew or something.
It's true, it's kind of goofy.
It's my first start as an engineer.
Because it is now.
I was using that GPS back then.
Internet advertising...
I don't know, maybe now.
Normal.
I mean, the Internet.
It's kind of normal for a web engineer.
I don't know, at that time, there wasn't that much yet.
If you're thinking of developing a system
Or something more mission-critical.
Or in the financial sector.
That way.
Something like that on the Internet?
You were still new.
Right.
Now I can get GPS in the background.
Because since I sent the GPS.
He waited a few tens of seconds and finally got GPS.
That was the time.
I know, right?
From all these places.
I can get GPS.
Or maybe it's bluetooth.
With all kinds of things.
Things like figuring out your place in the world.
It didn't used to be like that.
And at that time, it was still very run-of-the-mill.
What kind of service would that have been?
But map-based?
At that time, many people were looking for that store.
On a gourmet site or something.
It's like it can tell you where the nearest store is.
Since that time, it's been called "location games.
There were games that used location data.
It's still not as common as it used to be.
It was on KyoPon or something like that.
Legendary.
Great machine.
You don't even know what you're doing.
I see. I see.
I still think you should use GPS.
Nowadays, it's really more like a "location game.
They don't even say "location game" anymore?
The word "location game" itself is not so common anymore.
After a lot of that stuff came out.
It's called "location games.
Like, really, those traveling people.
While riding a bus or a bullet train.
All over the country, really.
Anyway, it's like getting a GPS.
You've been through a lot.
I see, a geo-media community.
But I'm glad that someone like you came.
I'll tell you what, this isn't a "location game" matchup.
We'd talk and stuff.
That's right.
Those were really interesting times.
Many new services were born.
Sure, you know, like a programming contest.
But it's still something we've been serving.
Back in the day.
I really need to put something on the map now.
That's what I'm talking about. I can search only for barbecue restaurants.
Make a map.
It's one service on the Yakiniku map.
I couldn't even do that without programming it, though.
Nowadays, it's all about BI tools.
Or maybe you can just map it.
JavaScript and libraries.
There's a lot going on.
Put it on CMS or something and show it on a map like this.
Or showing polygons.
You can do so many things with it.
That word "mashup" was so popular.
Maybe Google will release an API or something.
I really don't know if there are any map-related services.
It's much easier to make.
And then the iPhone came out.
Finally, in the background.
Tell him I can get GPS now.
That's really where it started.
There's been an explosion of different services.
Mashup awards and other program contests
I've been on the receiving end.
But the people who made it...
I guess it's Google now.
And then there was Mr. Fujii.
I'm still in that SUN MICROSYSTEMS or something.
I just went to a recruiter.
It's like a non-profit organization or something.
Something about a bunch of people from that area.
When I was doing the contest.
Really its a mashup
If anything...
The word "mashup" used to be a musical term.
Come to the programming world.
It's hard to explain APIs to people.
I guess so.
I'm that reporter from the newspaper.
I got into a fight with a reporter from the newspaper.
They're going to put the service up.
I don't know if it's an API.
He wants to change it to Japanese.
It's even harder to understand in Japanese.
I wish someone would understand this.
Tell them they need to write it in API.
Then he told me to use katakana.
No, you don't know any better.
A.P.I." in katakana.
So just say it.
Then the other members of the group asked me if I had any questions.
I'm just trying to make you look bad.
You asked me to speak more softly.
From now on, I'll use katakana for that kind of thing.
Even in those terms.
Because it's going to become more and more common.
API is called API.
Tell him I want him to write it in the alphabet.
On the phone, on the phone.
It's amazing.
But I couldn't communicate at all.
Katakana API after all
The World
I feel like I've come to terms with that.
It's so normal now.
It's just a normal, generic API.
Even from non-engineers.
Let's do it via API.
I've started to hear things like.
APIs were not that common back then.
Yes, well, to begin with.
such
We need to get our computing resources out there.
The very idea of exposing it via API.
Hey.
It wasn't there, was it?
I knew it was something.
Well, that's where I originally got involved with data.
It's just a trigger.
The data we've created.
Why go public?
And it's called open data.
I even came up with a concept.
Why do you have to do that?
I don't get paid that much.
And then there are things like that.
But then again, I was involved in open source.
That's the way it is, isn't it?
We have to create our own value now.
Open Source and
It's like an open API, but also a little different.
And Google is still doing this for free.
By exposing map data through APIs.
Including that Japan.
The world's geographic information industry
You've already changed so much.
It was already too rough. That was...
Until then, I'm selling map data.
That's what I was in the business of doing.
Create an application on top of it.
Like making money from the traffic of it.
What is a model?
It's not so easy anymore.
It's not like I was born in Japan.
It's symbolic, though.
I knew there was something to it.
I wonder if it's just a coincidence that the first one was also a coincidence.
In the course of my work.
Or there's some kind of GPS that can do this.
I just wanted to come over there.
Well, did you enter Sirius or something?
first
Yes, well, at first.
I knew that GPS was interesting.
He came in and said he wanted to do a GPS-based service.
Eventually, when I got into Sirius, it was pretty much that.
That ad-serving service requires a medium, doesn't it?
There wasn't much media at the time.
Not yet.
Send me that GPS.
It was a world of waiting for a few tens of seconds.
We need that many media.
And that's why I decided to hold that study session.
Do a free conference.
It's like a way to boost the location-based industry.
I established the Geo Media Summit.
Oh, yeah.
yes
That's right!
Geo-media is also a thing.
It's a term we all coined on our own.
It only works in Japan.
Yeah, I know.
Nowadays, geomedia is not a word.
It's not much anymore.
Yes, it was Geo x Media.
Until then, and before that.
I was told it was GIS or something.
That's not what I meant.
Because we need media services.
I was like, let's get that going.
That's why I started this community.
I think it's all connected to the present.
I have a feeling.
I'm often asked by the local government...
What is the difference between GIS and geomedia?
You know, the kind of inquiry.
I had it on the web.
Well, I made it up as I went along.
I knew the word "geomedia" was
The GIS industry is old-fashioned, isn't it?
The surveying and various other things.
From the real map industry
Until it develops into data.
There are some very well-established people who are doing this.
It's like Google or something.
He jumped in with a bang.
This is a long-established company and this is a venture.
Pretty much, that confrontation.
I was very much in that era.
I think that was the most fun.
Yay, interesting.
To be able to witness such a drastic change in the industry.
That's really interesting.
Maybe even when the Internet was created.
Something about that geomedia system.
That old, that industry and that new place.
I don't know.
We'll have to admit it to each other.
There were times when you were kind of buzzing.
It's something about being part of a community when you're in that area.
It was the most fun I've ever had.
Certainly when something is changing.
So that's what it means.
But until then...
Did the community do a lot of things?
There are so many IT communities now.
You're kind of a symbol, Seki-san.
It's not like I was doing it.
You were a participant.
A lot of what we call communities.
Yeah, there's been a lot going on.
I was the first one to debut in the community.
I still remember it.
There is something called Zope (Plone).
It's a CMS.
So we used it internally.
Heh.
I heard there was a study session at the
I applied for that study group.
when one does so
Why don't we do that lightning talk?
I was told.
What's that?
It's a presentation.
No, no, no, no, no.
I've been using it for a bit.
It's not something you talk about in public.
I don't have it.
By the way, when I told him I was doing this.
He said, "No problem, it's only five minutes.
He asked me to talk to you because you're funny.
I told you.
I was so nervous talking to him.
When you first joined?
oh, yes!
That makes me nervous.
But then...
I've been getting a lot of feedback.
Oh, he said it was great fun.
From there, it's pretty much all open source.
Join the community.
That Zope (Plone) stuff.
Like going to study groups.
And OSC.
I'll be at that event or something.
I've been talking to a lot of people.
Or help set up a booth.
That's the kind of thing you were doing.
I see.
There's something about community.
I'll take the geomedia type stuff.
I'm really glad I started this.
I thought it might be the first.
I can't imagine being a participant anymore.
The World
I can't help but feel like I'm presiding over it.
No, no, not at all.
I don't feel like there's a gang leader in that OSC group.
I was just a regular participant.
I see.
If you want to start up your own business, you can do so.
To some extent, I was thinking about how community works.
I'm not sure what to say about that.
Did you find it?
No, it's not like that at all.
What is that in the first place?
The idea of having a community like that.
It's not like that.
The Geo-media Summit is
We're not a tech community.
Well, it started out as just a drinking party.
Oh, I see.
It's a way to boost the industry.
I'll give you a technical talk.
And not only that, but also...
I'm in the media industry.
Of course, there were a lot of non-technical people like this.
So, I have three conditions.
That "openness, neutrality, and emphasis on interaction".
People from various industries gather here.
That particular
For example, for Sirius Technologies.
If you do that, the competition won't be able to come.
Let's not do that.
That's what I'm doing with the other people in the open.
Neutral.
He said we should discuss the information openly.
It's just that...
There's something off the record, too.
It's a gentleman's agreement.
Let's have a drink and talk in a place that emphasizes interaction.
We were talking about something like that.
It was really exciting.
It was good, though.
Well, then...
It's more like a study group from inside the company.
Right in there.
It's just a place where you can come if you know someone.
How much is the maximum?It's pretty big.
Well, yes, maybe up to.
I think it became a place where about 300 people gathered.
At first, it was really that location information.
The idea is to get together with people who can drink with this latitude and longitude as a snack.
It hasn't changed when we got to 300 people, though. There.
It was a heavy drinking party. A New Year's party, I think.
And then 50 or 60 people showed up.
It was a very dense situation.
It's usually always thick.
Because this is interesting.
Let's make it more like a study group.
That's how it started.
And even then, it was not just Sirius.
Also, Sirius has a venerable image.
Very.
I've always had an image of you as a venture capitalist.
That's what I'm talking about.
There were a lot of people who were doing it.
There were a lot of them, like Mapion.
It was interesting to see the participation from so many different companies.
These people are definitely geo-media types.
Or Yahoo.
Yes, I know.
How long did you do the Geo Media Summit?
Probably not more than ten years old.
That long, I see.
It's been about six or seven years, I think.
Okay, that's long enough.
That's why Mr. Seki was so interested in the Geomedia Summit.
Representative, when you decided to quit.
He said he's quitting.
It's not like Seki-san made an announcement.
Or maybe the announcement was made in a more confined area.
I've announced something.
At some conference.
"Seki, you're not representing us anymore.
And then, somehow, it became a rumor.
Seki, you're not representing us anymore.
Just like in that movie.
I had one just like it.
It's like, "Hey, I'm quitting the club.
Just like that one.
What's the real story?
Something like that.
Rumors started to spread.
Anyway, there's something about the next Geomedia Summit.
I have to show my face.
It's like it's some kind of retirement ceremony.
Are you really going to stop?Oh, but you won't stop.
Something like that.
It was like a buzz, and it really came in waves!
Heh heh heh.
I see.
Me at that time
I didn't say much at that time.
I don't know if it was there.
I thought you looked like Seki.
I don't know where I said that something.
I've been hearing rumors of something like this on the World Wide Web.
It's like I'm becoming...
I'm sure he knows that.
It's not like you're going to say something else somewhere else.
At any rate, the rumors keep coming.
I'd like to know what you think is so funny.
I remember how we all said it together.
Is that so?
So where did you do it?
Something like that in Odaiba or something.
Oh yeah, the one in Odaiba.
In a technology exhibition.
I got a frame announcement.
It was a long time before that.
It's been a while since I've seen you.
At that time, I already said I'd quit representing Seki.
By now, we've all heard about it.
That's what I'm talking about.
that's right!
Yeah, and when I get there, I'll make an announcement.
Oh, you mean they knew about it before you announced it.
Maybe that's why he said he'd quit something.
I was wondering if they were going to make an announcement when I got there.
I said, "Odaiba is too far," but I went there.
So you went in and didn't announce it?
Oh, there it is.
Maybe they did it in Odaiba.
But it was all very smooth.
At any rate, I'm sure there's some kind of
We were talking about looking at that map of the river.
Everyone or something was really excited about that one.
How can you get excited about this and drink alcohol?
We all say things like that.
There was just something about "OK, Google".
Someone brought it back from overseas.
Even if you pronounce it.
People can't hear "OK, Google.
Or something like that.
Something like that.
Really Geek Gathering
Earlier, there was that non-techie guy.
You said you were here.
I don't know about those people either.
It's a little bit like being in touch with the tech world.
I'm not a very technical person at all.
What's with the location information?
It's easy to imagine it as a service.
At the time, it was all about "location and something else.
It's a combination of things.
It was a new service that was taking shape.
It was easy to get into, too.
Right.
Yeah, it was still a bit early at that time.
Geo could have been the main character.
By combining them, services can be changed.
It was a time like that.
It's the norm now.
It's like I don't have to say anything.
So I've been trying to get some kind of geodata.
You said you distinguished it from data.
Data that doesn't have location information on it.
I'd rather deal with it in the Internet.
It's no longer something difficult to do.
It's normal.
Right.
From a geo-media type place.
So, it's like a first step.
Engineers. I know they did it to you originally.
I'm getting more and more interested in that side of things.
In the midst of doing service.
I went to a place called Social Issues.
Some kind of turning point.
You have a reason?
This is, after all.
Can I have this?
Tohoku earthquake (March 11, 2011)
I knew it. "sinsai.info".
I mean, the activities around it.
Mm-hmm.
Before that.
It's not that I wasn't interested at all.
Maybe I feel exactly the same as a normal person.
If it were normal...
If you live a normal life.
You want to do something useful for the world, don't you?
but
I didn't feel like I was actively trying to do anything.
I just had a thought.
When the baby was born.
Too much information about parenting.
I think there's still a lack of it on the Internet.
I was wondering if there was anything I could do.
Make the task a little more realistic.
It's just that I've learned to see it.
It was about a year before the earthquake.
The Great East Japan Earthquake happened in the middle of it all.
You've been delivering ads.
The ad serving service is
That's when it became completely unnecessary.
Yahoo! stopped advertising that ad, too.
Hmm, I see.
That's not the point.
So, in a nutshell, I'm out of a job.
Like there's nothing to do.
In the midst of all this, I came across "sinsai.info".
Using open source software.
I'm trying to gather information on crowdsourcing.
I've been involved in the
That was a great experience.
hmm
It's like this.
I'm, well, a geomedia guy.
You know, the technology you've developed.
That's what it's all about.
I think it might be useful in this way.
That's how you got started?
I don't know what to say.
That's because I happen to be involved in the open source community.
I'm involved in the OpenStreetMap community.
The earthquake happened, and I called immediately.
I was able to confirm the safety of my family and others.
So when you say, "What should I do?
With all of them.
Yahoo! was located in Midtown at that time.
Evacuate to that park behind Midtown.
Watching the news and stuff.
I thought this was going to be a big deal.
on the verge of
Mr. Miura, who represented OpenStreetMap at the time, said
People are on the mailing list.
I was sending you an email.
Now is the time to do something about it.
That's where the pan switches over.
Other people and stuff are working together now.
A man named Azuma-san.
It was used in Haiti the year before that.
With this open source
I said maybe we can do the same thing in Japan.
Tell him I'd like to try that.
That's it.
Oh, my God.
For now, everyone should go home for the time being.
As I walked home.
I did a lot of work on that email.
It's like I've been coding since I got back.
That's how it all started.
That's why it's not like that.
It's not like, "Okay.
I don't know, I just happen to know what I can do.
Like, it was right in front of me, so I just kept doing it.
And then, before you know it, it's like this.
And then, gradually, like this.
I wanted to know so many things.
It's like we're here now.
Like the OpenStreetMap neighborhood.
I was wondering if you were already asleep.
So many things are happening so fast.
A lot of people have already committed to a lot of things.
It's just that it's taking shape.
I can already see blah, blah, blah.
What's this like, who's doing this?
I knew that movement was
Great impact!
I think there was.
After all, even from the perspective of Seki and the others who are doing it.
It's like I'm changing in some way.
Something before that.
I was a victim of the Great Hanshin Earthquake.
I don't really have any information.
Even at that moment.
Some newspapers have internet access.
I've been through a lot.
But to the general public.
It's nothing like that.
What happened?
The roof of my apartment building fell down.
That's all I was thinking about.
But there was a burst gas line or something.
It was like I shouldn't even be here.
But I don't even know where to go.
Or maybe you don't understand at all.
I really don't have that kind of information.
The Great East Japan Earthquake.
I saw that something this big happened again.
But the way the information was conveyed at that time was different.
So fast.
But you were just in Chicago.
There was that Drupal conference.
I've been over there.
We were just getting here.
I got there at 23:30.
A while ago, in the middle of the night.
I took the cheapest flight I could find.
I came in the middle of the night and had nothing to eat.
But it's a bit of a hotel.
The restaurant on the first floor said they'd open it for you.
I don't have anything.
Tell her it's easy if it's easy.
There's Wi-Fi and stuff.
As soon as you told me and I connected it.
After about ten minutes.
It was shaking, shaking, shaking.
I was like, "What is this?
Anyway, I went back to my room and turned on the TV.
I was already overseas.
I'm already getting a lot of information, and it's already exploding.
It's called a video.
But then I thought, "Well, I'll just do something here.
I think it was some student.
A junior high or high school kid on the Internet.
What about Nico Nico Douga, was it a tweaker?
It's like a tweak now.
In the past, I don't know, maybe UStream.
Run it out with something.
And my friend's house.
I was just at a friend's house in Kesennuma.
I was just about to be swept away.
I mean, what?I understand.
I'm not sure if it's a good thing or not.
Wait a minute. I want to wait a minute.
There's so much information coming in.
I experienced it myself.
In the old days of the earthquake, there was no information at all.
I was just wondering if you could help me out with some information.
I've been in some of these fields myself.
Even if there is, there's nothing you can do about it.
Seki and his team's activities made me feel like a buzz.
I'm taking that information and giving it form and value.
Something like that.
I've been in some open source stuff.
I'm not sure how to create value with it.
I don't have that many positive ideas or anything.
I don't know what to do.
That's what's happening.
I really wish I could make this and sell it.
That source code, if you're selling it in a stiff way.
There was a time when the world was good.
Where it's not.
There was a part of me that felt like I was on the right track.
There's something amazing I can do.
somehow or other
It's like, if you use your head, it might be there.
It was like a change of mindset.
Even though I wasn't there.
It was amazing.
Can I go home for a while or not?
I've been looking at information in places like I don't know.
All that time.
You're looking at the Internet and wondering if you can do something.
Where people do this.
I just wanted to see if I could do something.
It's the only place I can be involved anymore.
It's remote.
You were there yourself.
So, Seki-san and the others.
I've been watching the activities of
And the facts that come out in those places.
The media will bring it out.
It's not that the facts are different.
There's a huge difference in temperature, isn't there?
something like this there
I had this feeling of bewilderment.
So, like this, two computers and a TV.
I got something for you from somewhere.
I asked the hotel staff to bring it to me.
It's like another TV.
I've been monitoring you.
Oh, I see.
That's what I'm worried about when we're apart.
I'm not sure which is true.
I'm pretty sure that's what he's saying over here.
I know it's true.
Something about the death toll in the news in Japan.
And it's not increasing at all.
Some foreign media got it wrong.
I don't know, like 8.1 on the Richter scale or something.
Something like a million.
The person who died.
Something like M for million.
I introduced it in a way like that.
It was a bit of a false alarm.
I wonder if I'll get one of those.
When you're wondering what's going on and what's going on...
Well, it's more like information.
Get it right, data as data.
I'm not sure if I'll be able to do it.
It's so righteous.
Something to give us data all the way up to that point.
I've been mulling it over, wondering how it's going.
I knew this was very true.
You need to get that data right.
He said he'd put it out there for everyone to see.
You can't help but enter people's senses, can you?
Like how you want it to look.
I thought that was inevitable.
I can't help it.
How can we cut down on that?
He asked if I'd show him.
I think it's very important.
I felt it so much at that time.
Right.
You know, we...
What do I mean by open data?
I knew I needed it.
It was that "sinsai.info" of the Great East Japan Earthquake, wasn't it?
say
For example, we want to map the information of evacuation centers.
I want to see where the shelters are.
How many people have been evacuated?
Everyone wanted to know.
I'll tell you what.
I was thinking of going to the shelter to get the data.
So, no.
Even if it's on a website or something.
Or maybe the address isn't listed properly.
Also, it's copywritten.
I can't just copy it without permission.
Can I post that as data?
And even if you talk to the local government about it.
First of all, the phone was disconnected.
Even if I could get through to him.
I'm sorry about that.
It's like using a tight phone line for a permit like this.
But, well, there are people who need it.
Like making a phone call.
However, even if you ask me a question.
They don't know what I'm talking about.
So you can't answer.
I don't even know who to call for confirmation.
I don't know what it is.
They said no.
I couldn't post it.
This should be done in advance.
If you could just remove that copyright.
We can do whatever we want over there.
It's out there.
(esp. of men) one's prime (approx. age 30)
They think they're getting it, too.
It's a combination of many things.
of course
Make sure you have the data right from the start.
It's important to be able to use them.
That's what you do in an emergency.
It's natural for them to be low on the priority list.
I guess I have to do it in peacetime.
That's what I've learned.
That was a pretty big experience.
When I made my first website in 1998 or so.
Create a website for your area or something.
There, you know, regardless of the local government.
There's a lot of information out there, and I'm not even local.
I was just trying to get some information.
I think we can get that kind of information to the people we want.
I thought.
Send an email to the various municipal neighborhoods.
I asked him to give me the data.
That e-mail was posted on the wall.
The World
What do you mean?
Something from this guy, with no name.
He said it was extremely inappropriate to receive such an e-mail.
Give me the data.
It's like they're already sending me this stuff.
It's like there's some kind of crazy person out there.
The entrance to the city hall at the very beginning.
Someone told me it was posted.
Do the same thing with your website.
You know, the guy who does the regional ones.
There weren't many at the time.
I can't believe I'm still making websites.
It was posted.
Now that municipality is also using open data.
I'm glad to hear you're doing so well.
But it's not like that.
Well, data is data.
It's collected through taxes, and it belongs to the local government.
So this is how it's going to go public.
I've already published it as a website.
I managed, though.
That still needs to be protected.
I've been thinking about this since the Great East Japan Earthquake.
Even at times, you were still strong.
After all that...
It's called open data promotion.
It became a national policy.
The Great East Japan Earthquake was a disaster for the country as well.
It was really important for the release of such data.
It's changed, hasn't it? From there.
From that activity
In a place like Code for Japan launch.
Are you going to move on in Seki-san's mind?
That's right.
I mean, it's like...
You've used a lot of things.
Its "sinsai.info" is
oh dear!
I got a few page views.
The people who actually go on that volunteer trip.
To get the information.
You know, I can just about figure it out.
Very useful.
I'm not sure.
After all, there were those two things.
One, as I said before.
If we don't do it right in peacetime.
See you next time
There's no point in doing the same thing from scratch.
I know you will. You have to do it.
It's the newspaper, isn't it?
Some people like local media.
I'm gathering a lot of great information.
There are only a handful that make it to the paper.
This information is a waste of time.
I'd like to be able to share more of these things.
Something like that.
That's one of the things I was thinking at the time.
I just want to make sure that information gets out there.
The other is to begin with.
This technology
What we've done...
I wonder how much of this really helped.
Something like that.
At least those who were there.
I don't even have a phone.
The Internet itself.
Like, I can't get through.
I was talking about something like no batteries.
It didn't help, did it?
There are stories like that.
And then, during the reconstruction period.
It's like, how can we use that little bit more technology?
I wanted to help in some way.
That's why we have to make sure that we have the right technology.
I want to use it. I want people to use it.
Something like that.
Well, actually, I happen to know some people who do.
You said you had a chance to visit the site.
I think it was about a month after the earthquake.
You've already been in many areas.
Kamaishi.
All kinds of things.
It was a very tragic scene.
say
A month. It's hardly changed at all.
So I was there.
Most of the time, they say, these things are useless.
Affected areas, especially the coastal areas on the front lines
In places like...
That car license is much more useful.
It's more than a technical thing.
What is it that you need help with in the first place?
I'll talk to him.
There's no way I could have come up with that.
Oh, my God.
I don't understand what you're saying in the first place.
It's like...
However, he said I should do this.
I don't even have that knowledge of the field to speak of.
I feel like I'm on the edge of my seat.
There's something I can do about all this.
But of course I can't do this on my own.
It's pretty hard to tell.
I'm a little depressed.
Then I went to the volunteer center in the Tono area.
It's a relatively big place.
Everyone stays there for a night and then
Places like going to the affected coastal areas of each region.
And you're the head of the center there.
What I want to do with IT
There are so many!You said.
So it actually happened.
I'll have to manage reception and stuff.
Something about how hard it is to do in Excel.
You want to make your website better.
Something about a guy cleaning photos.
You want to make it easy to find out what you're doing.
I could think of a lot of things to do.
In fact, do something like a hackathon.
Like making prototypes and stuff.
I'm glad you liked it.
I felt like I was being saved.
I don't know what it is with these sites.
People who can bridge the gap between people who understand technology
You don't have to be very knowledgeable about it.
Someone who says, "I have a lot of work to do.
I thought it was really important.
We really need people like this.
There's something that can stand between us.
I thought it would be nice if I could do that.
Well, I've been there and done that.
I was just growing out of it.
So...
But I still don't know how to do it.
He said he wanted to do something like that.
All I had was a fuzzy feeling.
Founder of Code for America
By Jennifer Pahlka.
I've published a TED Talk.
That was in 2012.
You had a great flash of inspiration when you saw that.
I thought it might be fun to do this in Japan.
Something about sending that engineer to the government.
Maybe do some prototyping.
Creating a local community.
It's something I can understand.
You're talking about a lot of things that could be done.
if it comes to that
I wanted to try it in Japan.
He said he started Code for Japan.
Flow.
The earthquake was a very big trigger for that.
I wonder if
I don't know if I've ever heard of open data before.
It also conference in 2010
When I went to London.
I'm sure there's something between open source people and
Maybe he's involved in open data.
I'm working on that separately.
I'm working on that open source and doing that too.
I had a lot of things like that.
He invited me over quite a bit.
Do you have any plans after this?
Open data
I don't know.
I have a little community thing.
I was like, "What is that?" and the more I heard about it, the more I listened.
Oh, like it's never going to happen in Japan.
The idea is that you're in open source.
Just say it.
It's still not accepted in Japan.
But the idea is that it's rational.
I think I have a great base.
That rational thinking.
In the first place, in Japan, it is somewhat
It's not that I can't accept it.
Especially at work, if you're rational about it.
You can't take money, and all that.
In the engineering world, there were things like that.
I was wondering if it would be difficult.
Here comes something like open data again.
But then...
London has had a rough time of it.
We've got to take care of ourselves.
step
That kind of movement?
When there's a problem.
I knew I couldn't be like this anymore.
I thought it was easy to get up.
I wondered what it would be like in Japan.
In 2010
I'm really thinking about it.
But that was then.
From a friend in that Perl community.
I'm afraid I can't make myself available for a moment.
I have friends coming from Taiwan.
He asked me to show him around Kyoto.
I don't even speak that kind of English.
Oh, no, I'd rather show you around on my own without you.
If you say so, that's the G0v (Gab Zero).
The founding member.
CL Kao (Chia Lian Kao, Gao Jialiang)?
or thereabouts
Like Audrey Tan (Tang Feng).
It wasn't like Audri or anything then.
I don't know.
And there again.
Open data.
We were talking about civic tech.
Something like that.
He said that the people who are trying to do this are all around him.
But I guess there are a lot of engineers.
If you say something like.
Well, we were here as a couple.
The engineer is your husband, the engineer.
His wife was a journalist.
And something about Taiwan.
There's a lot of people involved.
Civic tech.
I thought Japan wasn't like that.
Even if you're not an engineer.
There's so much I can do.
That those people will move it.
They said, "Because it's there.
something or other
I wonder if that's how it's going to be.
I don't know.
While we are in an open source world.
We're going to make open data out of data that we've created somehow.
Wait a minute.
Like.
But moving on...
I'm sure data is absolutely important now.
called
A lot of things that were bothering me...
There's something that's been leading me there.
or perhaps I should say
I'm not sure.
That's the way we have to think from now on.
I don't think I'll be able to keep up.
As a great sense of urgency.
such was the case
There was, but...
I'm not sure what it takes to change something like that.
I don't really have it in me.
I'm sure you've heard of such disasters.
I don't know what happened.
Among Seki's
Was it very big?
Yes, of course.
If not for the earthquake
I'm probably not doing this.
Startup people
So he was a start-up guy.
if I had to say then
Overseas oriented.
He was happy to work abroad.
Now I see. In that sense, it's very domestic.
I tried my best to study English, but...
Not now.
I don't think I want to work abroad.
It's also a global place in a different way.
We can get involved, right?
In those days, you'd go over there.
For example, working.
So that's what you've been doing.
I see.
But so is the Corona this time.
I knew that crisis would happen.
That civic tech stuff is great.
He's very active.
Society itself needs to change.
That's the direction I'm going.
And this time, too, we'll have a digital agency.
I've been to the Code for Japan Summit before.
Get him on the morning show or something.
When we change the country.
The country will change.
Or maybe...
Is it possible to change things from the local level?
I gave a talk on the subject.
I don't know... I was just thinking about that theme at the time.
That's how the government works.
Local government.
Some of the people who were involved in the project came to see me.
That's the theme I had in mind.
I think it's something more in between.
That's what I'm thinking.
People who connect there
I'm like this.
Well, in a slightly neutral way.
I don't know if it's something the government wants me to do or not.
I've been working in a different area than my main business.
I do.
I knew what I had to do in the middle.
There's a limit to what I can do.
I'm just halfway through my training.
I wish I could do more for you after this.
It's not easy to do it there.
I'm not sure I'd do that in my day job.
I'm not sure if it's a budget issue or not.
You want me to do that on my own?
I hear it's different if you volunteer to do it.
I'm kind of stuck here.
in some respects
But at times like that, Code Four, it's like...
This is how it should look.
Just neutralize it there.
For example, if you take a job.
I knew you'd be working with 100%.
I'm asked to do these things.
In an activity called Code Four.
Then you do a little of this.
I'm gonna do a little of this.
I'd like to know what you think.
Bring it up and then have it take shape.
By the way, Code for Japan
Something like that.
I knew you'd bring it up.
Everyone brings their own.
It's not always easy to make that happen.
If it was in front of somewhere else.
SIers and the like.
Maybe they were pulling him up.
I don't know.
Something different about that too.
There's something a little more neutral in there too, something that's not governmental.
And not just citizens.
I'm hoping that these people will do something for me.
Surprisingly, that's where the cell will turn.
I don't know if I'm in the right place.
I just kind of took it.
I'm not sure what I'm supposed to do on my own.
There are some parts that are like that.
I've been working with Code for Kyoto (Kyoto) and others.
This is my job.
Something about going this far.
I wish I could do my job and do it right.
I don't know... I can't do it.
That kind of vagueness...
When I got involved in Code for Japan, I felt like
would you say?
That's what we're trying to do.
I'm wondering if there is.
if that's the case
Code for Japan and Kyoto (Code for Kyoto)
It's not like we're in the same position again.
And I'm getting a lot of stuff.
But I think Code for Japan is the way to go.
I don't know. This one here and this one there.
There are places we can go.
Or maybe not.
I feel like it's changing shape.
Yes, I've been feeling that way a lot lately.
It's really early days now.
So it was like an open source community.
It's really grassroots.
I'm going to do what all those people want to do.
And that's how wisdom is shared.
I hear it's getting better.
Of course, anything made with
Release it as open source.
It looks like other people use it.
But it's not the only solution.
There are so many of them.
When it comes to changing the system like this...
doing something in a roundabout way
With the resources we have.
The things that we need to do...
a lot
I know you have.
And that's what I'm talking about.
There are areas where economic rationality alone is not enough.
There are a lot of them, and there's
The existence of Code for Japan is
little by little like this
Support those areas.
I wonder if it's becoming something like that.
I've been thinking.
For example, in the beginning.
Maybe I did last year.
The Tokyo Metropolitan Government's new corona infection countermeasure website
Well, I'm still working on it.
You couldn't have done something like that.
That's a job that I'm being paid to do.
But at a regular vendor.
I'm doing something that's not easy to do.
Something like that.
I'm sure it's a big part of his existence.
Yeah, I know. It's like...
You're going to be like Mr. SIer.
You have a little civic tech expert there.
or something, maybe.
As for the various paths.
I'm sure they'll find a way to make it work.
It's not like I'm going to be a regular SIer.
I know I'm not the only one who thinks so.
That's not funny.
I think so, and I don't.
I'd like to be in some kind of position.
Because it's already got a scale to it.
They already have a role to play in this.
It's not the same as that.
I guess that's what I'm aiming for.
Of course.
What do you think Code for Japan should be?
It's something I want to work towards.
It doesn't make sense to do something that can be done in a normal company.
Well, for example, the Tokyo Metropolitan Government's website.
If you can find another place to take over.
if it exists
It's like you're handing it off and on.
I think it is.
And now...
This is what I'm focusing on.
It's not just about economic rationality, as I mentioned earlier.
Mutual aid.
For those parts.
I'm talking about building a system that works.
I also think that doing what you want to do is the most important thing.
And it's the most fun.
It's about creating value for society.
It's in good condition.
Nothing like that.
That so-called GDP.
I don't use that as an indicator.
In that community, that's what I want to do, that's what I want to do.
Like, it's so much fun to do this.
can do each of the following
And it was well received.
And as a result, other people will be happy, too.
That cycle, the cycle that generates that value.
It's the birth of something like that.
I just thought it was really important.
In order to create such an environment
I knew that the local government
We have to change the way we are.
You know, it's something to start with, something to work with.
I need to hire more people.
Those areas.
Code for Kyoto (Kyoto) is also a good example.
I've been working with a lot of people.
That kind of
Something like a society of hands on work.
As a community well
I'll make it again.
For that
For parts that require some resources.
Code for Japan also
We're going to support them in various ways.
I'd like to do more and more experiments like that.
I've been thinking.
Code for Japan has just started.
I'm working on something called the DIY City Project.
And that's exactly what it is.
It's not about DIY, convenient, smart cities.
Not a society that pursues convenience and efficiency.
How rich the region is, how rich the culture is.
To creating it.
Citizens have a great hand in this.
Like, are you getting paid for it?
That's what's important.
Set KPIs like this first
Create KPIs for abundance.
After that, it's just a matter of moving your hands.
Or being evaluated.
To move those hands.
I'm calling it a DIY toolkit.
Let's make more and more of those weapons.
I mean, I'm working on it.
In many ways, the areas that we will focus on in the future are
Although its called a DIY city project.
Maybe you can be a little more specific.
The idea is to work together in various areas.
That's where I want to come from.
I may have said a few words at that time.
When I was really young, I was kind of...
I'm talking about the marketing job sector.
I've been working as some kind of assistant.
And then, well...
To study together.
He told me to do it with him.
What kind of town would be ideal?
That's what they made me write.
Figure it out, or rather, draw it out.
My painting had only economic rationality.
The only things that exist in this city are things that make us productive.
Look at that.
Well, it's more culture.
Education is the key to the development of a city.
It's very important.
We need to have more of that perspective.
He told me I was making a mistake.
He was a senior I really disliked.
I don't know if that's what he said to me.
I learned a lot, I guess.
It's one word that I still remember.
When I think about something.
In my case, I just couldn't help myself.
Or when I'm working on a proposal or something.
It's easier to understand if you say something about that KPI.
I've been to those places.
But I want to.
What I originally wanted to plan and do?
That's not what I'm talking about.
I'll drop something into the document.
That's what happened.
What's so interesting about that?
When you feel like you've disappeared somewhere...
That's usually what's involved.
Oh, my God. Like this.
It's a word I'm aware of.
There's something about the richness of DIY cities.
I don't know if that's the kind of place that would come in.
Until now, it's just been this stuff that Seki-san writes.
And I've seen it.
I didn't know much.
Oh, yeah. Too bad.
I don't know, I'm more of a...
Mr. Seki said
In Japan... open source...
I was just saying something.
I've heard that you should volunteer.
I don't know if I should be getting paid or not.
You know, they can go off on crazy tangents.
But overseas.
In America, for example.
You have the money over here.
We have that kind of service mentality.
That's a good balance.
Hold something.
I'm just trying to do the right thing while doing the right thing.
Like I'm making money.
Something like this.
I thought it was really rare in Japan.
That's how I feel about you, Seki-san.
The only reason I can say this is because there's another company.
I've got that life under control.
Of course, it is important to be able to live properly.
I don't know.
This is what it takes to do this.
I'd have to say something.
Of course you're in a position of authority.
I'm in a position where I have to say that.
I don't know, it's like that for me too.
When you're doing something good.
Something about money and stuff like that.
I just want to go there without doing anything.
But see, I'm doing such a good job.
I'll make sure you get this much.
Like, you're thinking of giving it to him, too.
It's like you're reading the air.
It's like...
I can't always say it right.
But that place is open source.
And it's not like that.
I'm using something that's licensed.
There money is expensive.
And I don't mean
I have to juggle something.
To be independent.
I knew I had to be independent.
Isn't that kind of thing necessary?
I don't know, I just can't help it.
Now, when we get down to it.
It's all about economic rationality.
I'm going to go to extremes.
The balance between the two is very important.
It's a balance.
Anything.
There are a lot of people who try to see things in terms of zero and one.
I get that a lot.
It's like volunteering or rewarding exploitation.
I don't know.
The rewards of work aren't just money.
I mean, it's obvious.
Of course, there's more than just this money.
Or growth.
Do that normal, creative thing.
Or joy.
It's a combination of all these motivations.
People are on the move.
conversely speaking
Then you're supposed to pay for it.
You're not going to do it.
So that's where this job comes in.
Or ask for it.
And the person making the request.
Right now, it's about the other person.
What is your motivation?
Like, are they moving me?
Well, you know, for what you did for me.
What can I do to show my appreciation?
The idea of the richness of a place like that...
I'm just wondering if it's really necessary.
You're going to pay for that.
The person making the request.
If that person is bound only by economic rationality.
Like, how much do you need?
That's not what I meant.
That purpose was so much fun.
Everyone should be in on it.
If you want to make that thing.
You know, there are a lot of people who work with their hands.
Something about the Tokyo Metropolitan Government's website
There are a lot of people involved in this right now.
There are a lot of people who haven't paid that money.
But I'm not forcing you to do anything.
And it's not.
I'd like to thank you from the bottom of my heart.
It's really like this.
We're communicating with each other every day.
Well, that's something, isn't it?
It's going to take some doing.
So money is more than money to pay.
I've spent a lot of time and effort on it.
Well, someone who understands such things.
It's all good.
Some people are like that.
You'll have to pay for it.
That makes a difference, doesn't it?
That's the point.
I wonder if it's necessary, like richness of mind.
I guess.
The state of Code for Japan
How long has it been since you've been to a place like this?
Since we started up.
It was launched in October 2013?
It's been a little over seven years.
It's a bit more of a second phase.
I wonder if there was a second phase.
I think we're in phase three.
something around there
I think it's time for a change.
I was looking at it from the outside, too.
I think Code for Japan will be able to work together in this way.
Code fro Kyoto (Kyoto).
Or my day job.
Maybe we can do some stuff.
There are many things that I think
I can see it in myself.
I don't know if that's what you're doing.
If you could just do something like this.
Maybe the cells will turn better.
I've been seeing things like that myself.
Even from the representative, Mr. Seki, who is in the room.
I wonder if this is how things are going to change.
I think there's something to be said for that.
I don't know how to make it more and more.
He wants to go like this.
I think that's what we're doing right now with the DIY cities we just talked about.
A little further down the road.
What can I do for you?
I knew it was something.
Once again, I was able to meet with people who are active in their respective areas.
I'd like to do something that involves collaboration.
I've been thinking.
Like the DIY city I mentioned earlier.
I'm trying to create a bottom-up society.
The country's assistant CIO.
I do a lot of that kind of work.
That's exactly what Japan is.
There are 1,741 municipalities.
I just think it's great.
How to make use of the diversity of it while
Or create that better ecosystem.
Things like that are important.
I knew it was one of them.
You definitely need a local community.
In the past, it was more like a neighborhood association.
It's like that mutual aid community.
The part that's been holding us together.
This is how urbanization works.
But with urbanization and population decline
in that manner
It's gone.
And to be able to hold it together like this again.
I've always thought of it as this kind of civic tech community.
It's named after each region.
They say there's a community.
I think it's very important.
And Code for Japan.
What kind of relationship do we have?
It's like we're getting richer.
Win-win for both parties
Win-win is not the right word, it's something like this.
It's like we can lift each other up.
That's what I'm aiming for.
So there's that.
Code for Japan has been working on its
Or a base.
This is how the community works.
It's like a bridge between the two.
The people of each region
They say you can do what you really want to do.
That's the kind of environment we need.
I hope to make it in the next few years.
That's what I'm talking about.
Kyoto, for example.
Especially since we are not a town that communicates much to the outside world.
It's the Inner Circle.
There are so many community groups.
That's why we have to do it ourselves.
When we do Code for Kyoto.
I thought I had to make a difference.
So.
Code = source, because it's programming.
I heard that IT is going to change something like this.
It's important to write code properly.
That's what you said at first.
But I've been thinking it's getting different.
Something like that.
I can help you from the IT place.
I've been talking to the local government.
I've been through a lot myself.
Some of them I get for my work.
I was trying to get involved.
I don't know.
It's not there.
But I've also been working with other people in the community.
I knew it was different.
It's kind of IT-based.
When you say you're going to do it with IT, it's like...
Please create a facebook page.
Or something like that.
It's not like that.
I don't want to do those little things.
It's just something that happens.
There was a time when I didn't know what to think.
I have a much different perspective now.
I'm also thinking that it's not there.
That's pretty much everyone.
You say you're trying to figure out the value of what you do.
A national push for open data?
There are a lot of problems.
I think I'll do that.
this way
That's what I'm saying, let's make use of it.
I don't know if I'd use it, but I'd have to get it out of my system.
It's called "utilization.
I have to admit that I'm not sure how I feel about that.
But the fact that it's being used so much makes it all the more important.
How can I make it worthwhile?
If anything, I'd like to know what's going on with the people at Civic Tech.
Maybe there's something to it.
The number of people who are like that has been increasing dramatically lately.
I get a lot of questions and inquiries about it.
How can I get an introduction to someone from Civic Tech?
I've seen a lot of things like that.
I also think this is a very good trend.
I was just thinking.
Something like us.
There are some places that do this in the community.
I'm sure it's going to change.
I think I'm at a very important turning point.
I'm sure it's some kind of code four.
People working in the community.
And the people who do it in this way.
I think that's what he's feeling.
I think that's a great idea.
You know, it's been pretty exciting in each of those areas lately.
It's called a brigade.
I'm looking at the code for each region.
Pretty much that tech.
Someone who is not on the technology side.
I've been working on it.
I've been thinking that there's been quite an increase.
You know, the so-called
Someone who can use that technology.
I'm tempted to use technology.
If we do that from the beginning.
It's not going to work.
In my past activities.
He knows what he's doing.
You know what?
That so-called...
When you have a drill, you want to use it.
But that's the hard part.
And it's not technology-driven.
You can't be issue-driven.
I mean, that's both places.
When I think of some business service.
Isn't this task-driven?
There is a challenge, though.
But if you go that way...
Really that way.
It's what I wanted to do.
So let's go technology-driven.
Then again, I'm not sure I'm solving the problem.
This is a difficult place.
It's very important to move your hands.
In the process of prototyping
I'm seeing a lot of things.
I'm going to throw that away to some extent.
And you have to have the courage to say.
I've been working on this for a long time.
I've been in a lot of meetings.
I can't make any progress.
The answer to that question is two wheels.
I need it.
The technology side is already becoming a commodity.
Use that real low coding tool.
Quickly, is this what you mean?
You can do something like that.
Engineers can work in the next phase.
The first part of what you have to do is
The techs are a little quiet.
I think it would be better if it was more like that.
I will, though.
I caught a glimpse of it earlier.
The government's assistant CIO, for example.
It's been done.
There's a lot of bottom-up stuff going on here.
I'd like to talk about community activities.
In support.
Now the country's
You do that kind of work, too.
Something there.
Is there any difference in Seki-san's mind?
Or is there some kind of continuation there?
It's something I've been working on.
That's going on.
I'm...
From the rather early days.
I have a strategy of using multiple job titles.
That makes sense.
I thought you said you had a lot of business cards.
You've got all kinds of hats.
It's very convenient.
Only in that country.
Only in the capacity of assistant to the national CIO.
There's some information you can't get.
You can see it only when you're inside.
I understand that it's a structural issue.
The more you know about it, the better.
It makes it easier to make suggestions.
So it'll be easier for us to work together.
in that sense
I'm really the assistant CIO of the country.
A small place.
In a place called Nishiawakura Village with a population of 1,400.
I'm also doing CIO.
It's just a matter of broadening your horizons.
From various layers
I'm just trying to be someone who can see things.
Just do it.
It's a continuation of the earth in that sense.
Sometimes I'll give my opinion as a technician.
Sometimes it's really like this.
With a certain amount of consideration for the feelings of the bureaucracy.
For example, criticism.
That's a fair criticism.
It's probably counterproductive to talk about it that way.
It's the same.
How would I know?
for that reason
I've been in many positions.
In that sense, it's a continuation of the ground.
as Seki.
What do you want to do in the future?
Something like that at the end.
Would you mind telling me?
I am.
I want to quit Code for Japan as soon as possible.
Oh, I see.
One more "Seki, I'm quitting" on the web.
I'll flush it.
It's not like I'm quitting next month yet.
It's like everyone is here to declare their resignation.
Yeah.
I'm not quitting yet.
I'm just thinking about the generational change.
I'm old enough to know better.
After all, it's like Civic Tech.
Especially.
We should pass it on to the next generation as soon as possible.
That's what I'm thinking.
Innovation is...
Something like that is built on generational change.
I have a
I knew it.
A lot of really young people since last year.
I've been working with Code for Japan.
Yes, it's a huge increase.
He's very good.
Oh, my God.
It's like a natural way of thinking about civic tech.
It's ingrained in you.
And so those generations in
I should be the star of the show.
That generation.
Then when I said I wanted to do something...
At that time.
I just want to make sure that the environment is in place.
Then I could quit, I thought.
That's as soon as possible.
Make that happen.
I'm something different.
I'd like to do that.
I have a feeling this is just the beginning.
Always.
Geomedia is no different.
I think it's just the beginning.
You're looking at a lot of different things then.
Not for me, anyway.
I'm not good at growing that organization.
It's your personality.
It's amazing what happens when you start from scratch.
The World
But when I look at young people now, it's true.
What is Civic Tech?
You don't have to say.
I'm trying to do something.
It's a normal thing.
I really feel that.
Yes, sir.
Come on.
When I saw "Seki, I'm quitting.
Please tell me in secret.
I'll broadcast it to everyone.
Thank you very much.